Oh, good heavens!
噢, 老天！
Look, what's going on? Who are you?
诶, 这怎么回事？你们是谁？
We are Dominators.
我们是统领者
Both of you stand by that wall.
你们俩都靠那面墙去站着
- I will not.
- Oh, now, Jamie...
- 我不去  - 噢, 现在 Jamie...
- Oh, no. They're not going to...
- We're meant to be obeyed.
- 噢, 不好, 他们不是要...  - 必须服从我们
- Not by me, you're not.
- DOCTOR: Jamie!
- 我可不干, 你别想  - Jamie!
What... All right, if you insist.
什么...好吧, 如果你们非得这样
(WARBLING)
Doctor, I can't move. Help me!
博士, 我动不了了, 帮我！
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
It is pointless to struggle.
挣扎是没有意义的
My Quarks have used a molecular force
to bind your bodies to the wall.
我的夸克用了一种分子力将你们与那赌面墙绑到一起
What's he going to do with us?
他打算对我们干什么？
Alien races are occasionally of use to us.
外星种族偶尔对我们也是有用的
I intend to probe your physiological makeup.
我打算要探究一下你的生理结构
Do what?
做什么？
- Doctor, can you not do anything?
- Don't struggle, Jamie. Keep still.
- 博士, 你不能做点什么吗？  - 别挣扎, Jamie, 静静呆着
Toba. Quarks, attach force units.
Toba. 夸克, 加载强制设备
- Activate. -(WARBLING)
激活
RAGO: Visor.
面罩
Transmatter focus probe.
fixme
Brittle skeletal structure.
易碎的骨骼结构
Reasonable flexibility.
灵活性尚可
Certain amount of muscular force,
could be marginally useful.
肌肉有一些力量, 可能有一点用途
- Vulnerable, only one heart.
- TOBA: Intelligence?
- 脆弱, 只有一个心脏  - 智力呢？
A simple brain. Signs of recent rapid learning.
大脑简单．有近期快速成长的迹象
Still, somewhat crude.
但还是, 比较原始
Shall I prepare the other specimen for scrutiny?
我应该准备好另外那个标本进行检查吗？
No, they will be identical.
不用了, 他们会是一样的
Conserve power.
节省点能量吧
- TOBA: Are they dangerous?
- No, they are physically inferior.
- 他们危险吗？  - 不危险, 他们体能比较差
- So we destroy them?  - No.
- 那我们消灭他们？  - 不要
- It is possible we may use them.
- What for?
- 我们还是有可能利用他们的  - 用来做什么？
- Workforce.  - We've got the Quarks.
- 用作劳力  - 但我们有夸克啊
We must conserve their power, you know that.
我们必须节约它们的能量, 你知道的
But why do you want...
但为什么你想要...
Command accepted.
接受命令
Set up a reaction test.
准备一个反应测试
Test this one.
测测这个
As soon as your friends return,
等你的朋友们一返回
they will follow you and Cully
in the second capsule.
他们就会坐第二辆穿梭车来找你和Cully
Wouldn't it be better
if all four of us went together?
如果我们四个人一起走不是更好？
- Travel capsules only take two.
- Number one ready.
- 旅行穿梭车只能坐两个人  - 一号已经就绪
There's nothing to be afraid of, you know.
没什么可害怕的, 知道吗
Oh, I'm not frightened.
I'm looking forward to it.
噢, 我不害怕．反而很期待
Come on, let's try and stir up
a bit of action in the capital.
来吧, 我们试试看能否在首府搞出点事情
You really mustn't believe
Cully's wild tales.
你真的不能相信 Cully 那些天马行空的故事
(DOOR HUMMING)
I will dial for the capital, Cully,
if you don't mind.
我要拨通首府, Cully, 如果你不介意的话
I see. Frightened I might disappear, eh?
我明白了, 害怕我可能会消失, 嗯？
Well, it has been known, hasn't it, Cully?
哦, 大家都知道的, 是吗, Cully?
It'd be a joke if it happened
this time, though, wouldn't it?
如果这次发生的话就会是个笑话, 是吧？
And if we are to use these Dulcians as slaves,
而且如果我们要用 Dulkis 人作为奴隶
there are certain qualities you must look for.
有一些品质你肯定得寻找
Obedience, strength, sufficient intelligence
to make them of use,
服从, 有力气, 有足够的智力以便我们能利用
but not so much as to make them dangerous.
Is that clear?
但也不能太高以免带来危险．明白了吗？
Yes.
好的
Uh, what are they saying?
啊, 他们在说些什么？
I think they are arranging
for some sort of test.
我觉得他们在组织某种测试
- Test? What for?  - I don't know.
- 测试？为了什么？  - 我不知道
I thought I heard them
mention the word "intelligence".
我觉得我听到他们提到了＂智力＂这个词
Oh, you mean they're going to
find out how clever we are?
噢, 你的意思是他们想搞明白我们有多聪明？
Yes. Or how stupid.
是的．或者是有多蠢
I wonder which is the more important to them?
我在想哪个对他们更重要？
Well, then, Zoe, what were you doing on the island?
好, 那么, Zoe, 你们在那个岛上做什么？
Well, nothing, really, just looking around.
哦, 没什么, 真的, 就四周看看
- But didn't you know it was dangerous?
- No. At least not at first.
- 但你们不知道它很危险？  - 不知道, 至少一开始不知道
Oh, Cully, how can your conscience allow you
噢, Cully, 你的良心怎么能够允许
to expose innocent and foolish people
to such dangers?
把天真愚蠢的人带入如此危险的地方呢？
- But I didn't take her to the island.
- Oh, nonsense.
- 但我没有带她去岛上  - 噢, 胡说
I know all about Cully's Adventures Unlimited.
我可知道 ＂Cully探险无极限＂是什么
- You know, but why didn't you...
- Well, you weren't doing any harm.
- 你是知道, 但你为什么不...  - 还好, 你没有造成什么伤害
- At least we thought you weren't.
- But it's illegal.
- 至少我们觉得没有  - 但这不合法
To prosecute would have given you open publicity
起诉你正好顺了你意, 给了你面对公众的机会
and it wouldn't have reflected very well on me, either.
而且对我的影响也不好
I see. Why can't I be treated as an individual
我明白了．为什么我就不能被当作一个普通人
and not always as the son of the Director?
而不要总是被当作议长的儿子看待呢？
Now then, young lady, tell me exactly what happened.
现在, 女士, 确切地告诉我都发生了什么？
Well, I landed with the Doctor and Jamie.
哦, 我和博士、Jamie 一起降落到这里
- In Cully's ship, yes?  - Cully?
- 坐着 Cully 的飞船, 是吗?  - Cully?
- Oh, no. We came in the Tardis.
- And what is that?
- 哦, 不, 我们坐 TARDIS 来的  - 那是什么？
- It's an advanced craft for travel.
- Goes through time and space.
- 是一种先进的旅行船  - 可在时间和空间里穿梭
I think this joke has gone far enough.
我觉得这个玩笑开得过火了
There you are, I knew he wouldn't believe it.
看吧, 我就知道他不会相信的
But it's true! You can ask the Doctor and Jamie,
但这是真的！你可以去问博士和 Jamie
they'll be here soon.
他们很快就会到这里了
What do you hope to gain by this foolishness?
你编这些鬼话是图什么呢？
But it's not. I told you when
we spoke on the vision link.
不是鬼话, 我们在视频电话里对话时我就告诉你了
Three people have been killed,
a spacecraft has landed,
有三个人丧命了, 一艘飞船降落了
radioactivity has disappeared
and there are robots on that island.
辐射消失了, 岛上出现了一些机器人
Now, I may have a pretty inventive mind,
喏, 我可能是有一个异想天开的脑袋
but I wouldn't have dreamt up
that lot, now, would I?
但我不会做梦做到这个程度, 对吧？
And no doubt you will confirm all this?
毫无疑问, 你可以证实所有这些吧？
Uh, well, I haven't actually seen
the spacecraft and robots...
啊, 只是, 我其实还没有看见飞船和机器人
Oh, so it seems we only have
your word for it, Cully.
噢, 那我们就只有你的证言了, Cully
And experience has taught us
how little that can be relied upon.
而经验已经教给我们, 那些话有多么可值得信赖
What's he up to now?
他现在要做什么？
He's arranging some sort of
intelligence test, Jamie.
他要搞某种智力测试, Jamie
JAMIE: You mean those wee shapes
in that big box? What for?
你是说那个大盒子里面那些小积木？什么目的？
Yes, well, we'll have to put
the right shapes into the correct holes,
是的, 嗯, 我们必须把积木放入形状对应的小洞里面去
it's quite simple.
相当简单的
Well, if that's all it is,
a kid of two could do it.
哦, 如果仅此而已, 一个两岁的小孩都可以搞定
Yes, that's what bothering me.
It's too simple.
是的, 这是困扰我的地方．它太简单了
You moved.
你动了
I'm free. What about you?
我松开了．你怎么样？
- Me, too.  - Come on.
- 我也是  - 快点
(QUARK BEEPING)
TOBA: Well?
QUARK: Molecular force expended.
- 怎样？  - 分子力已经消耗完了
Order required.
请给出指令
-Are the specimens to be refused?
-No.
- 需要拒绝这些标本吗？  - 不用
- What are you going to do with us?
- Quiet! Over there.
- 你打算拿我们怎样？  - 安静！到那边去
Sit.
坐下
Well, thank you.
好, 谢谢你
Attach force units.
加载强制设施
(HUMMING)
Hands. Through there.
两手, 穿过那里
Power.
通电
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
That will be repeated at regular intervals
那会隔一段时间重复一下
until the puzzle is reassembled.
直到该谜题被解开
(WHIMPERING) Oh, no!
噢, 不要！
Begin.
开始
(GRUNTS)
JAMIE: Hurry up, Doctor.
快点, 博士
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
DOCTOR: Oh, my hands!
JAMIE: No, the square bit...
- 噢, 我的手！  - 不, 方的那个...
- DOCTOR: What?
- JAMIE: No, not the star,
- 什么？  - 不, 不是星形那个
the square bit in there!
那边那个方形的
(BUZZING, DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Detach.
松开
Doctor. Doctor.
博士, 博士
Now, where's that...
诶, 哪儿去了那个...
Here. Take it. Sniff, sniff.
这里, 来, 嗅一下, 嗅一下
-(DOCTOR COUGHING)
-That's it.
好了
Come away. Come away
from that fearful contraption.
闪开, 别靠近那个可怕的东西
- You all right?  - Yes, I'm all right.
- 你没事吧？  - 是的, 我没事
What were you up to? That puzzle was easy.
你在搞些什么啊？那个谜题很简单啊
An unintelligent enemy is far less dangerous
一个不聪明的敌人其危险性要小得多...
than an intelligent one, Jamie.
比起聪明的家伙来, Jamie
- Hey?  - Just act stupid.
- 嘿？  - 只管装傻
- Do you think you can manage that?
- Oh, aye, it's easy...
- 你觉得你能搞定那个吗？  - 哦, 是的, 很简单...
Attach force units.
加载强制装置
You two, over here. Sit!
你们俩, 过来．坐下！
- Oh, thank you.  - Thank you. Oh.
- 噢, 谢谢你  - 谢谢你, 啊
Power.
通电
Now, get off.
现在, 下来
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING, DOCTOR YELLING)
- I said, get off. - Oh, but...
- 我说了, 下来  - 哦, 但是...
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING, BOTH EXCLAIMING)
- Try it round here.  - You're surrounded.
- 试试走这边  - 你被围住了
- Well, how do we get off?
- There is a way, find it!
- 那, 我们怎么下来？  - 有一种方法, 找出来！
- Test complete?
- TOBA: These creatures are useless.
- 测试结束了吗？  - 这些生物没什么用
- Strange.  - You question my report, Navigator Rago?
- 奇怪  - 你质疑我的报告吗, 导航员 Rago?
I find it at variance with what we already know.
我发现这跟我们已经知道的情况不符
- I don't understand.
- The weapons we saw earlier,
- 我不明白  - 我们早先看见的武器
could they have been devised by such apparent simpletons?
它们可能会是这么明显的傻瓜设计出来的吗？
- You think that there were...
- That we will find out.
- 你觉得他们是在...  - 我们得去探究明白
Message to fleet leader.
传送信息给舰队首领
"Materials readily accessible, please proceed to refuel.
＂原料已可获取, 请前来补给能量＂
"Investigating potential slave labour." Transmit.
＂正在调查奴役劳工的可行性＂, 发送
(DEVICE BEEPS) Come with me.
跟我来
- But every time we try and get up...
- Jump!
- 但每次我们试图起来... 跳！
DOCTOR: Jump?
跳？
Jump.
跳
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
A simple circuit completed by your bodies,
你们的身体接通了这个简单的电路
you obviously know little of electricity.
显然你们对电力基本不懂
Elec... Elec...
电...电...
Are you such a fool?
You have intelligent eyes.
你真是这么蠢吗？你有一双聪明的眼睛
I will continue the test personally.
我得自己来继续这项测试
- RAGO: I said, what is that?
- Well, it's some sort of gun, isn't it?
- 我说过了, 那是什么？  - 哦, 是一种枪, 对吧？
- Explain it to me.
- Well, I don't know that I...
- 给我解释一下  - 哦, 我不知道我...
- Firepower potential?  - Huh?
- 火力?  - 哈
- What does it do?  - Oh! Oh, I see.
- 它是做什么的？  - 噢！哦, 我知道了
Well, guns kill people.
对, 枪可以杀人
- Is that what you wanted to know?  - Fire it.
- 你们是不是想知道这个？  - 开枪
Well, I don't think...
这, 我不觉得...
You have to put something into it first
and it comes out here,
你必须先放点东西进去, 然后它从这里出来
as far as I remember.
我记得是这样
You. Fire it.
你，开枪
- Oh, I wouldn't know how...
- Do as Dominator Rago says. Fire it!
- 哦, 我不知道怎么... - 按统领者 Rago 说的做, 开枪！
(STAMMERING) Well, I'll try. Um...
好, 我试试．唔..
I think you put a cork
or something in...in there...
我记得你要放一个木塞什么的到...这里...
Jamie. Jamie, be careful.
Jamie, Jamie, 小心一点
- I'll get the hang of it, Doctor.
- Jamie, be careful.
- 我会想起来的, 博士  - Jamie, 小心一点
Wait, we don't understand guns on Dulkis.
等等, 我们 Dulkis 星上面的人都不懂用枪
We haven't used them for hundreds of years.
我们已经几百年都没有使用过了
So,
这么说
you don't understand guns.
你们不懂用枪
(EXCLAIMING)
Are you sure?
你肯定吗？
Yes! It was the clever ones who invented them.
是的！是那些聪明人发明了他们
- The clever ones?  - Yes, they...
- 聪明人？  - 是的, 他们...
They lived long ago, you see.
There aren't many of them left.
那是很久以前的事了, 你看．他们现在没几个人了
They stopped us using guns and things.
他们不让我们用枪这些东西了
- There are two distinct types on this planet?
- Yes!
- 这个星球上有两类不同的人？  - 正是！
How many of these clever ones are there?
这些聪明人还有多少？
Well, there are not many.
We don't like them much.
哦, 并不太多．我们不太喜欢他们
- They tell us what to do, you see.  - Good.
- 他们告诉我们该怎么做, 你看  - 很好
I see.
我明白了
There is nothing to fear from these primitives,
对于这些原始人没有什么可害怕的
and the others sound as if they're pacifists.
另外那些听起来像是和平主义者
So they are useless.
所以 他们都没有什么用
They have a small labour potential, nothing more.
他们只有微弱的劳工潜质, 很有限
- Shall I destroy them?
- No, we must conserve power.
- 那我该消灭他们吗？  - 不, 我们必须节约能量
- But why do...
- We have nothing to fear from such creatures
- 但为社会那么...  - 我们不用怕这些生物
It will be a waste of energy to destroy them.
消灭他们也将是对能量的浪费
Leave them!
别管他们了
Stay away from us and the Quarks.
离我们远点, 离夸克也远点
- Oh, yes, sir. Thank you very much.
- Yes, Master.
- 噢, 好的先生, 非常感谢  - 遵命, 主人
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
- Am I glad that's over.
- Yeah, me, too.
- 很高兴终于结束了  - 是啊, 我也是
They're a bloodthirsty lot,
these Dominators, aren't they?
他们是帮嗜血的家伙, 这些统领者, 是不？
Aye. What do you think they're after?
是．你觉得他们有什么企图？
I don't know.
我不知道
That message they sent.
他们发的那条消息
"Material readily accessible."
"原料已可获取"
Some sort of mineral deposits, do you think?
像是在挖什么矿, 你说呢？
Then this fleet of theirs would refuel,
land and pick it up. It makes sense.
然后他们的舰队就会来补给能量, 登陆把它取走．有点道理
What do they want the Dulcians
as slaves for? They've got the Quarks.
他们为什么想让这些 Dulkis 人做奴隶？他们已经有夸克了
Aye, nasty little beasties.
是, 很恶心的小怪兽
Hey, Doctor, they've gone.
嘿, 博士, 他们已经走了
We'd better get back to that survey place,
Zoe will be wondering what's happened to us.
我们最好回到勘察点去, Zoe该担心我们怎么样了
I think you're right.
我觉得你说得对
I've got to make them believe me,
before it's too late.
我得让他们相信我, 否则就来不及了
- Well, what are you going to do?
- Get some evidence.
- 那, 你打算做什么？  - 找点证据
Will you come back to the island with me?
你愿意跟我一起回到岛上去吗？
All right. But how do we get past
the council out there?
好啊, 但我们怎么绕过外面的议会呢？
Through my father's rooms. Come on.
穿过我父亲的房间, 快点
We'll have to steal a travel capsule somehow.
我们必须得想法偷一辆旅行穿梭车
Well, I can manage that all right, but...
哦, 我可以搞定那个, 但是...
- Well, what's the matter?  - Your clothes.
- 怎么, 什么问题？  - 你的衣服
- Not exactly Dulcian, are they?  - So?
- 很不像 Dulkis 人风格, 是不？  - 那怎样？
We'll attract too much attention.
我们太引人注目了
We'll never get past the capsule managers.
我们永远没法通过穿梭车管理员那一关
Still, no problem.
好了, 没问题
We can always fix you up
with some Dulcian garments.
我们还是可以修正这个问题, 弄点 Dulkis 人的衣服
- Where from? - Clothing dispenser unit.
- 哪儿有？  - 服装分发部
There's one in my father's rooms. Come on.
我父亲房间里面就有一个, 快来
This will take you direct to the capital, Doctor.
这可以直接带你去首府, 博士
Your young friend Zoe is already there.
你年轻的朋友 Zoe 已经在那里了
And no doubt Director Senex
is awaiting your arrival now.
而且议长 Senex 无疑也在等着你的到来
- Oh, this is splendid. (CHUCKLES)
- Hey, Doctor, what is this?
- 哦, 这太帮了  - 嘿, 博士, 这是什么？
You know I hate being put in a remote...
你知道我讨厌坐进一个远程...
Now, perhaps we can get on with our work.
现在, 也许我们可以继续工作了
QUARK: Unknown creatures approaching.
有不明生物靠近
-TOBA: Destroy?  - No.
- 消灭？  - 不
Investigate.
先调查
- It's enormous.  - So Cully was telling the truth.
- 很巨大  - 看来 Cully 说的是实话
- BALAN: Was he?  - TEEL: But Balan...
- 是吗？  - 但是 Balan
Where are the robots?
机器人都在哪儿？
Inside, perhaps?
里面, 也许吧？
But it's empty.
但里面是空的
Look, there's a map of the island.
看, 这里有这个岛的地图
QUARK: Stand still.
站着别动
But you are not Dulcians!
但你们不是 Dulkis 星人!
Where do you think everybody is?
你觉得所有人都哪儿去了？
Destroy.
消灭！
Destroy!
(QUARKS WARBLING)
- Cully, what's happening?  - I don't know.
- Cully, 发生了什么？  - 我不知道
- ZOE: Oh!  - CULLY: The door. Quick!
- 噢！  - 去门那儿, 快！
Stuck. It's stuck.
卡住了, 门卡住了
We're trapped.
我们被困死了
(ZOE SCREAMING)